[Music]
hi everyone Welcome to our session on
what's new extending co-pilot using Al
code I'm Derek Jew with me uh Julia
Sandy and enrio let's get started so on
the agenda for today uh we'll do a very
small recap on what's in our developer
tools then uh Julia will talk about
what's new in the prom dialogue I'll
continue on talking about um token
counting and function calling Julia will
take over um talking to us about uh
keeping the models current and sendy
will come in talking about manage and
shareed AI resources and then you go
will end it off with top questions so
let's get started so developer tools
recap um so some of you may have worked
with our AI module or our promp dialogue
but for those who have not there is the
session what's new designing and
developing generative AI experiences for
your extensions this is from a previous
launch event so you can find the YouTube
link there um and it's available for
everyone so just to do a small recap um
for those who have not seen this before
this is the prompt dialogue um so this
is for the marketing Tech suggestions um
you can see this is the result uh when
it has generated a marketing text uh in
this prompt dialogue there is the keepy
bit regenerate cancel options it also
allows you to um change your parameters
for example tone format and emphasis and
these are things you can play with uh
and configure in the prompt dialogue so
another example that uh we have is with
bang reconciliation so this one looks a
little more simple the basis of it uh
you have to keep it and you have
discarded how but there's no changing of
parameters at the bottom as per
marketing Tech
suggestions um additionally we have the
AI module which is in the system
application uh for working with Azure
open AI specifically for large language
models so you have uh calls to text
completions getting the embeddings or uh
chat completions I do want to highlight
um it is not for image for example with
e uh or transcribing Speech to Text uh
with whisper
um the modu also gives you ease of
control and viewing of the co-pilot
capabilities within your environment and
it also gives you uh Telemetry uh
allowing you to track like a
capabilities registration usage and what
errors you might find so now Julia will
talk about uh what's new in the prom
dialog Julia thank you Derek so let's
talk about it Derek showed up the prom
dialog to you and I'm going to tell you
what's new in this release first of all
now we can provide concise instructions
to help users get started they will be
displayed uh displayed as an
instructional text if you update the
instructional text property on fields in
your prompt area in the prompt dialogue
so to achieve the displayed
instructional
text if you update the instructional
text uh on this input text field it will
display this text it is worth mentioning
that it is not meant to be used as
example prompts this is the general
instruction to help your your users
understand what is the expectations of
them to input into the prompt
dialogue when it comes to providing
understanding and prompt templates we
have prompt guides coming to you in that
uh this book icon is displayed uh on the
on the prompt
dialogue and after clicking you can
input there a lot of templates to help
your users understand the bread of the
prompts that you uh
created so for example you get one or
more prompt guides that will act as
prompt
templates and to do that we have created
a new area in the actions on a prompt
dialog page type which is the prompt
guide area and then you input actions
that then can replace the text on your
field inside as presented here on the
screen what's more you can group those
prom guides in case you have more than
one to help your users for that simply
create a group inside the prompt prompt
guide area on the prompt
dialogue outside of the prompt dialogue
we have copilot actions that can be
displayed uh on lists list Parts
worksheets and standard dialogues in
order to draw attention and launch your
prompt dialoges as you can see on this
screen they are then displayed on the
bottom of the page all of your actions
uh co-pilot actions on that page as well
as in the
menu how do you implement such a copilot
action again there's a new area in
actions on list list Parts worksheets
and standard dialogs as I mentioned and
it is called prompting where you can put
your actions such as the previous one
displayed draft with
co-pilot I've talked about the AL side
of the new prom dialogue features that
we have but this session is part of a
pair if you want more about generative a
experiences how to design them when and
where to use compiled actions you should
check out what's new designing
generative a experiences where yakob and
Surin will talk about it and now I'll
give it back to Derek for token counting
thank you Julia um so token
counting what is this for so token
accounting allows you to count the
number of tokens that will be used by
your input before sending a request to
Azure open AI so specifically it's the
input and it does not count your output
because the output requires that do have
been generated
already um and now what are tokens so
tokens are specifically they are used by
the model because the model does not
take in words or it does also doesn't
return words they work with tokens so
for example with an input tell me about
the solar system the tokenized version
these numbers um the spaces are there
only for our readability so for example
with the first one 41551 that would
represent tell um and this is not an
exact representation uh however it's
what the tokenized version is it's not
always a one word to one
token um and in this case we have seven
tokens so why is it
important um so why you should you token
count um you would like to evaluate how
many tokens are going to be used because
then you can estimate what your
potential cost is um because your cost
and number of tokens you're going to use
are related so for every thousand tokens
there's Associated amount of cost
depending on the model that you're using
it's also important to know when you're
use um or how much tokens you're going
to use because a model has a limit to
how many tokens there are uh that it can
actually take in as input and now if you
have a prompt
when including the data that you're
going to send in is greater than the
number of tokens available for the model
um you're going to have to split that
request up into multiple requests so
this is also very beneficial for you to
know the exact number of tokens you're
going to use so that you can determine
all right how you're going to split up
your requests uh for each uh request
you're going to
make now how do you use this um the
methods can be found in the aoi token
code unit and we have methods per model
so for example um get GPT 35 token count
get GPT 4 token count uh get other token
count and DG token count uh one thing I
wanted to highlight is that these more
these methods are versin agnostic so
whether you're using um GPT 4 uh January
version or GPT 4 June version it does
not matter because they're all GPT 4 um
and also whether the difference between
GPT 4 and gbd4 turbo there's also no
difference in the tokenizer being used
as such the same function will work
across all of
them uh as of right now the methods do
not include our um provided system meta
prompt um but that will be
coming uh additionally I would like to
point out so when you're using this um
for example here where we call get GPT
35 token the input is of type secret
text and why is that uh and that the
reason for that is because your input we
consider that to contain your
intellectual property uh which is the
system meta prompt that you would have
used uh whether it's ours or your own uh
When developing your co-pilot
capability next up on function calling
so firstly what are tools uh tools are
like code interpretor knowledge
retriever or when you're building your
own uh with function calling um you may
have played with the on GPT um and these
are similar to how they'll work here um
so what is function calling uh it allows
you to describe functions to the
assistant model uh and have it return uh
the functions that should be called
along with the arguments uh that should
be put into those functions the function
to be called and arguments depend on the
user input uh given to the
assistant what benefits does function
calling bring
so it's able to then extract key
information from natural language and
allow you as a developer you to use them
as Arguments for your functions so let
me give you a few kind of scenarios that
this can be used for um determining and
intent of the input the natural language
um for example if you have functions to
look up documents or items so uh example
two examples of those would be if your
uh user says I need items from the last
um invoice now you know uh it's able to
then determine hey I actually need to do
a lookup for what documents uh this is
uh or another example is I need to R uh
bicycles and then that will be a lookup
for
items uh a larger example would be uh
you receive an email and in this email
they would like to purchase some uh
items so firstly you need to determine
okay what's the intent of this email
um if it's is it just a regular email or
would they like to purchase
something from there then once you
determine okay this is a purchase uh uh
intent now have the model to extract the
um the content for uh creating a
customer and there you can then also
extract the items that they would like
to purchase and then create a sales
invoice and send that along to
them so how does all this kind of look
like here I show you the um HTTP request
I'll be showing you the AL code in a
little while I want to point out what
are the important parts that make up uh
function calling so for the request part
you have the name so in this case it's
the get current weather and this is
important for us developers it's not so
important for the
model the important bit is the
description now the description tells
the model what does this function
actually do um it allows it to then
understand like okay if the uh user is
asking something about weather this may
be the function I want to end up
calling uh then you have parameters in
this case my function um get current
weather takes in two parameters um one
is location and the other one is
units and lastly you have a uh key uh uh
required so required basically tells the
uh model that hey these are requir per
um arguments that I need return to me so
in this case I'm only telling it hey I
need the location um whereas the unit uh
can either be blank or it can be filled
in depending on what kind of context is
gathered from the
input and on the response of what the
model returns to us um there's the two
calls
array and in that part uh it has the
name of the function that uh is to be
called so in this case get current
weather and then there are the arguments
uh with the values that should be called
uh with that function so in this case it
has location which says San Francisco CA
um and the unit that says uh
Celsius so how does all this look like
in Al so this um setting up your
capability and your authorization Etc
are all part of the session I had
mentioned earlier um so I will not go
into details about that uh however we'll
start with how you add your tool to the
chat messages so here I'm adding my tool
and it calls get weather uh co-pilot
function and I have my get weather
co-pilot function here where it actually
just reads um text into my Json object
and returns that I do know this is only
for demonstration purposes this is you
should not be putting your um function
uh as text in your code like this you
should always retrieve that from
isolated storage or Azure key volt for
example uh because your description as I
had mentioned these we cons can be
considered IP because they're describing
what the model should do with um the
function now we come back uh to the
overall function um next up I'm going to
set my tool choice so the twool choice
basically tells the model hey I want you
to always run this function uh and in
this case it's called the get current
weather I'll go into a bit more detail
um after this example of uh the pros and
cons of that um next up I'll add a user
message to simulate a user uh actually
typing in something of what is the
weather like in San Francisco um from
there I'll call get um generate chck
completion for it to go call a open Ai
and there I'll check whether it's been a
success or not if it has not I'm going
to throw my error so I know what it is
uh however if it's a success now I need
to actually interpret okay what is the
uh response that came back so I read it
into my Json object and then process the
response so how does the processing look
like so on the right you see the same
response that I had shown earlier um and
the AR code on the left so firstly I
need to check okay hey are we calling
some kind of tool and in this Cas I want
to check if it's a function um so I take
that out um from the array and determine
what is the type and if the type is of
type function I want to continue because
that's the only um type that I'm going
to be working with here uh I take out
the name because I know I've only Built
it with get camera weather I just need
to validate this is the actual function
that it is calling and from there I'm
going to now extract my arguments which
I'm going to put into my function that
I'm going to call so from there I take
out my location I know it is required so
it should be there
and I I I set the unit to be Celsius by
default um because I do not know if it's
actually going to be there as I did not
specify that it should be
required and from there I create a
function that basically puts in uh calls
get weather and it puts in the location
and the option uh of the unit and from
there I do some kind of call to a
Weather Service and return some
value um so the things I want to note um
where with set two choice you can either
put Auto which is the default um and you
do not need to set that or you can put a
specific function so with Auto uh it is
the default and if you use it with
functions the response can either be a
function or it can be a regular chat
response so you do have to take note
because if you expect a function and it
doesn't give you a function um you want
to uh handle that error properly and
whatnot um and if you set a specific
Tool uh specific function it will
guarantee that response will always call
that function however if your user
inputs something that is unrelated to
the function that's going to be called
um you will want to validate if uh the
arguments they giving is valid or not uh
that's all for function calling I'll now
hand it back to Julia to talk about
keeping
current thank you Derek let's talk about
current models are updated with new
features and improvements such as
function calling that direct just
described that means that each model GPT
3.5 turbo or GPT 4 will have multiple
versions such as for example a March
version and the June
version that means that the new version
May perform differently to the one you
tested on think about it over time the
versions that are released will perform
differently how can you make sure that
you still deliver the exceptional
quality of service I will talk about how
we take care of this in our Microsoft
build features so to inspire you to
implement a similar or a different model
that will enable you to keep up with the
everchanging versions of the models so
how do we take care of this we keep two
versions of each model available latest
and preview not that we don't really
specify if the latest is the June model
the latest is what we consider the
latest stable released model and then
the preview will be the new and upcoming
model that we want to make available for
testing before we update our production
features to the to this new upcoming
model and how do we implement this in
our features first we choose the desired
model and version for example my feature
will be working on GPT 3.5 turbo the
latest version that gives us a version
agnostic string that just mentions that
it's the turbo latest version and then
then before calling Azure open AI I map
it to the version AOA Azure open AI
version that I consider latest for
example the June
model and then generate the
response so let's talk about the process
that we Implement when the new model
version arrived let's say currently in
production my feature uses the turbo
latest uh and the Turbo preview function
both of the strings map to the model
version
a and then a new version B is released
so what do I do first I change the
mapping of the preview uh function to
map to version B the new released
version and then I notified the teams
using the latest uh version so then
developers can test on the new and
upcoming preview
version adjust the feature if needed and
then release that uh those changes those
adjustments to production and change the
mapping uh of the latest uh function to
also map to version B this way model
version B is released to production with
all the adjustment it needs and we can
wait for the version C to be released to
do this process all over
again that's it for keeping up with the
new model versions and now I'm going to
hand it over to Sandy to talk about
managed insured AI resources all right
uh thanks Julia um hello everyone I'm
Sarco I'm a product manager for business
Central and in this part of the
presentation I will introduce you to
manage and shared AI resources so as you
heard from my colleagues we have enabled
our partners on as isvs to build
thirdparty copilot features quickly
using developer tools for copilot in
business Central the current approach
that we use is to use a self-managed and
dedicated AI Resources by bringing your
own Azure open AI
account this approach has jumpstarted
and accelerated the exploration and
journey to infuse AI into their business
Central extension and solution in fact
in our recent AI Partners hackathon
alone hundreds of AI infused solution
were built so that's pretty
impressive but now when it's time to
bring this AI infused solution into
production at scale especially when they
are combining multiple copilot features
built by different partners or isv and
targeting many customer these approach
has a few challenges one of the
challenges is it's still unclear how
many Azure open AI accounts are needed
and who should bring them whoever bring
the a. account must satisfy the
requirements for responsible AI for all
features built on it it is also unclear
how to separately track the usage and
cost of multiple copilot features built
by different partners or isv as well as
features that used by many customer when
they share the same as your open AI
account and finally bringing your own
Azure open AI account still requires
manual efforts to manage those resources
you need to to do um to deploy to load
balance scale upgrade monitor or even
troubleshoot the relevant Azure
resources using the many different tools
available in Azure so consequently it is
time for us to improve and scale this
approach by introducing managed and
shared AI resources that eliminate that
eliminate these
challenges so you will not need to bring
any Azure open AI account anymore
partners and
isv can simply focus on satisfying
responsible AI requirement to access our
shared resources building their calet
features based on their intellectual
property and promoting just the value
added benefit of those features to all
customer also there's no need to track
the usage and cost of these resources to
run their copat features we will track
them all for all customer and we will
govern price and Bill resource cons fion
in a unified and simple way for all
copilot features that covers first party
and third party features right and
finally there's no more um need to spend
any efforts to manage those resources so
you don't need to deploy uh load balance
scale upgrade monitor troubleshoot these
resources anymore we will manage them uh
all uh in our um in our infrastructure
with always latest model version for all
customers so just like any other manage
and share resources in Business centrer
Online such as compute databases and web
service requests we will track
consumption and apply resource
governance to control how fast and how
much you can consume AI resources
ensuring fair use and as well as
unlocking um a value
proposition so how do we uh apply
resource governance to this managed and
shared AI resources we will introduce a
single AI resource consumption unit or
currency let's just call it for now ai
credit right and this AI um uh credit
will be convertible to various
consumption unit of supported AI
resources so it it'll be converted to
GPT 3.5 tokens or machine learning
prediction row etc etc but all you need
to know is just a simple single currency
AI credit right and this will assist a
customer to budget and control the AI
resource consumption and standardize
resource governance concept and measure
such as operational limit so we will use
operational limit ensure fair use among
user environment and customer by
controlling how fast they can consume AI
credits so high enough uh this limit to
satisfy the throughput requirement for
most customer and we will introduce the
concept of entitlement quota to unlock
the value of copilot enabled Min Central
uh for example we will introduce base
capacity in AI credit as well as uh we
can differentiate user licenses by
introducing acud capacity in AI credit
to make sure that most customer will
find their aggregated quotas of this
base and uh ACR capacity sufficient to
cover their aggregated consumption in
each billing
period and finally there will be a
concept of excess consumption so we want
to be able to provide flexible option
for only a few customer customer whose
aggregated consumption might actually
exceed their aggregated quota so this
customer can actually buy or purchase
additional um quotas or incremental
capacity also in AI
credits so this uh capacity based
resource governance and pricing will be
modeled and finalized through simulated
limit and quota enforcement in private
or public preview so you might ask when
is private and public preview you're in
luck because we already have our road
map outline for this managed and shared
AI resources private preview will happen
pretty soon after the business centrer
launch event a survey uh keep um keep
your eye open for sur a survey that will
be sent um maybe through a Yammer
Channel and uh selected partner orp will
be invited to participate in this priate
preview we will simulate limit and quota
enforcements against varying resource
consumption patterns to actually model
and finalize the proper limit and quotas
so we want to finalize the proper base
accruit and incremental capacity so the
ETA for priate review is pretty soon so
this 24x release so either 24.0 in April
or 24.1 in May right next public preview
we will introduce a new process to
satisfy responsible AI requirement
because you're not using a your open AI
accounts anymore so you will have a new
process uh to make sure that your
feature comply to responsible AI right
and then in public preview we will also
make sure that the proper limit will be
published and enforced while the proper
quota might also be published but will
not be enforced to uh to allow you some
grace period to uh get used to this new
Concepts so the ETF for public preview
will be the next release around 25th uh
25x version and finally General
availability is when the proper limits
and qu will be both published and
enforced the ETA still to be determined
or TBD depending on the preview
feedbacks and result um with that I'm
concluding uh my part of this
presentation and I'll pass the Boton to
my um colleague enrio thank you Sandy
that's very exciting so I'm enrio and
I'm going to cover the last part of this
presentation it's going to be about the
top questions we got about the developer
toolkit for copilot in business Central
these questions are a collection of
questions we got from you Partners as
part of your normal communication
channels for example through Yammer or
through Direct Communications with us
but also they come from the AI hackathon
we had a few weeks ago that uh Sandy
already mentioned um and we I just want
to say that we are very um inspired by
all the features you came up with doing
the AI hackathon and it's really great
for us to see how um you can help us
extend copilot and make our product even
better through AI let's start with the
top questions so why does the toolkit
not support the latest features of asure
open AI um I will answer this in a
second then Which business Central data
does aure open AI have access to and
then link to this how can I use my data
with aure open Ai and then last question
what model should I use for my scenario
let's start with the first one why does
the toolkit not support the latest
features on Asia open AI some of you
might have noticed some uh features and
capabilities that asure open AI um
offers such as the data sources
capability which we don't really expose
as part of our toolkit there are two
reasons for that the first reason is
that some of these cap abilities are
considered previous specifications on
Asia and AI side a couple of weeks ago
we got a new GA specification so a
generally available one but before that
it has been like several months before
we had another um GA specification and
in the toolkit we will not support any
preview specification um at all there is
one more layer to that which is we don't
necessarily want to support all the
features from Asia open AI into our Al
toolkit and the reason um is that there
are a lot and we need your help to
prioritize so uh engage with us talk to
us on Yammer tell us what you need and
then we'll prioritize the next feature
that we will make available in the
toolkit let's jump to the second
question which business Central data
does Asia open AI have access to the
answer is none our commitment is that
your data is your data you own your data
the models will not learn from your data
we will not feed all of your database to
the AI model nothing like that you are
in control
but that also means brings kind of a
follow-up question which is what if I
need to give my data to the model how
can I use my data with aure open Ai and
the answer is you need to fit all the
data that aure open AI needs into your
prompt um so this has some limitations
because prompts have a size limit which
means for example um if you have a
million items you cannot really fit
information about all these items into
the prompt you get you give to a open AI
so you need to be a bit creative for
example get uh the model to suggest you
the item category or maybe you know
already the item category so you can
filter down your items just to the ones
that belong to this category uh of
course permissions always apply so the
AI the copilot feature will work within
a user session and the permissions of
that user will be the ones that apply to
data there are other options for you to
bring your data into aure open AI such
as the data sources capability I
mentioned earlier um and just reach out
to us
tell us your scenario tell us what you
think and help us prioritize for example
help us decide whether we should
implement the data source functionality
in the AL toolkit or not and the last
question is what model should I use for
my scenario well our recommendation is
to use GPT 3.5 turbo whenever it fits
your needs because it's faster first of
all it's also cheaper for you and we we
have seen internally that it can cover
well most of the scenarios there are
cases such as if you have a lot of
tokens and you run into the token
limitation for your model or in case you
need like some more complicated AI
scenario so the generation quality with
3.5 turbo is not good enough then you
should of course upgrade to gp4 or even
GPT 4 Turbo but uh the bottom line is
just use the cheaper and faster model
that fits your
needs so with this one I'm done with the
top questions but I have one more bonus
slide for you we got a lot of questions
that are more generic about Ai and the
AI for example what are embeddings or
how do I write a good prompt or which
regions are available on aure open Ai
and uh we won't give answers to these
because these are more generic questions
but what we suggest to you is go and
explore the Asia open AI website um take
trainings there are some good beginner
trainings on AI and large language
models in Microsoft Lear learn website
uh so go take these trainings
unfortunately we don't have a BC
tailored training for you available at
this time but we still suggest go there
and learn and take some uh programming
language independent trainings so that
you can start learning and get started
with ai ai is here to
stay uh that concludes the my part and I
will also quickly go through some other
sessions that you might be interested in
in this launch event so as Julia
mentioned earlier there is a sibling
session to hours um which is designing
generative AI experiences go and have a
look at this session as well um it's
really important to design your
experience right not only to know how to
use the AL code behind the
scenes we also have quite a few sessions
that are about the end use of experience
with AI for example say line suggestions
with copilot or AI powered analysis with
copilot or E invoice matching with
copilot all these are end user features
but you as a developer might be
interested in seeing how we as Microsoft
Implement compilot and think about
compilot so go see these sessions as
well now the AL part of our toolkit is
actually open source is part of our
aka.ms /bc apps Repro in GitHub and you
can contribute to this reer you can have
a look at the code behind the scenes and
to learn more on how to do this and what
are the implications of this and how we
handle open source there is a great
session which is go open source with the
new GitHub repository for business
Central go and attend this session as
well some closing remarks I've said this
already I'll say it again Microsoft
cloud runs on trust AI is no exception
your data is only yours it's your data
the AI models are not trained on your
data they don't learn out of your data
we actually go through super restrictive
um compliance reviews that are even more
strict than what the law requires us to
do because we want you to trust us and
trust that your data is
yours I'll close with some links for you
you can learn more about our copilot Fe
on aka.ms
/bc I mentioned engaging with a team you
can do that and engage with us in on
Yammer you can see the forward link on
screen it's available for partners only
if you want to download some samples to
see how um you can make use of the AL
part of the toolkit and in general prom
dialogue and other parts of the toolkit
as well you can do that from aka.ms BCT
find the aure open AI folder these are
not production ready code but they just
to show you how you can interact with
the toolkit you can um apply for an Asia
open AI service key this is while you
wait for Sand's announcement to come
into place for everyone you can do that
aka.ms oi apply and finally um all we
talked about and all the toolkit
documentation is at aka.ms slbc start
coding with AI
learn then we have some generic Business
Center resources you've seen this a
billion times so I will just skip
through them um if you have to remember
one it's aka.ms /b all links are in
there and with that I conclude the
presentation and thank you all for your
attention see you next
time